Sam Garg

Hi! I've been building websites professionally for over 10 years and I specialise in responsive UI development using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

I have successfully delivered projects for clients all over the world including Scotch & Soda Amsterdam, Funda.nl Amsterdam, Vertu Luxury phones UK, Jack & Jones Denmark, Vero Moda Denmark and NineMSN Australia. I have also done freelance jobs for various small-medium sized businesses all around the world.

I have a lot of experience working in Scrum teams, building mobile-first, responsive, adaptive web experiences using the latest web-development technologies, delivering pixel-perfect implementations with good code. I also firmly believe in minimalistic design and minimal code. Less is more:)

Skills

- HTML(5)
- CSS(3)
- SCSS
- · Responsive Websites

- Social Media integration
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- Demandware

- Git Knockout.js
- Grunt
- WordPress
- Scrum

Experience

_

Bestseller, Amsterdam

Senior Front-End Developer (Contract)

Bestseller is a worldwide brand with 19 brandnames under its umbrella including Jack & Jones, Vero Moda and Only. They have 3000 branded chain stores across 70 countries. I was part of their Demandware E-commerce front-end team in Amsterdam.

- Vero Moda website redesign.
- A new product page with a new image slider and image zoom for all of their 19 brands including Jack & Jones, Vero Moda and Only.
- Responsive images for product pages and product listing page, to optimise load speeds on mobile and tablet devices.
- Lots and lots of cross-browser and cross-mobile-device/cross-tablet testing, to make sure every pixel displays perfectly on every possible screen.

Technologies: Demandware, HTML5, CSS(SASS), Javascript (Jquery), RequireJS, Grunt, SVG

DigitasLBi (Lostboys), Amsterdam

Jul 2014 - Mar 2015

Apr 2015 - Sept 2015

E-Commerce Front-End Lead Developer

Lostboys is the oldest digital agency in Amsterdam. Tight deadlines, continuous integration, and a fast changing environment is what we lived and bred.

- Built a new fluid mobile-first Pinterest style homepage for Scotch & Soda (a fashion label in Amsterdam).
- Building web-shop discount marketing campaigns for SCS (Sofas and Carpet Specialist big sofa retailer in the UK with 100+ stores), thereby maximising sales (Up to 400% during Christmas/New Year 2015).
- Continuously improving the website and web-shop for Vertu global (luxury phones brand from the UK), adding new product lines, and promotional campaigns. Multi-lingual and a pixel perfect classy UI, design heavy website.
- Lots and lots of cross-browser and cross-mobile-device/cross-tablet testing.

Technologies: Demandware, HTML5, CSS(SASS), Javascript (Jquery), RequireJS, Grunt, SVG

Funda, Amsterdam

Jul 2013 - Jun 2014

Web/Mobile Developer

Funda is the largest online real estate company in Netherlands. http://funda.nl gets about 8 million hits a day. They have an fast-paced Agile environment with an interesting mix of technologies, mostly Microsoft based.

- Improvements and bug fixes to their agent portal (makelaar admin) using ASP.NET MVC.
- I built an internal CRM for the sales team based on knockout.js, and Microsoft CRM api
- Building and maintaining HTML5, CSS and javascript for common web-views that they use across different apps on different devices.
- Develop and maintain mobile website http://m.funda.nl

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Jquery, C# .NET, ASP.NET MVC, Knockout.js, SQL Server 2012, Umbraco, Microsoft CRM 2011

NineMSN (Microsoft MSN), Sydney

Aug 2010 - Jun 2013

Lead Full-Stack Web Developer

I was actively involved in coordinating and developing, conducting daily Kanban stand-ups, mentoring fellow developers and liaising with clients and management. I worked in scrum teams building many projects:

- Leading news portal of Australia http://news.ninemsn.com.au
- A game competition for London Olympics 2012 users score points by sharing articles on their wall and are awarded badges on the basis of points. This was mainly built using the Gigya Javascript API (and JQuery)
- Marketing competitions for Mitre10 and Seek.com.au (HTML5, CSS3, Javascript)
- Ad Re-targeting Engine which helped NineMSN target ads based on user traits.
- Organising company wide Hack day (Hackathon) for 100+ developers, designers and data analysts.
- Building and supporting Gigya social platform from scratch, using Javascript, Jquery and RequireJs.
- I built an internal Error Logging Framework to log tens of thousands of errors every minute from 80 websites and build reporting on top of it.
- I was also involved in building a Ad Re-targeting Engine which helped NineMSN target ads based on user traits. Technologies: Html5, CSS3, Jquery, RequireJS, Gigya, ASP.NET MVC, Sitecore

Cloud55, Sydney

Jun 2012 - May 2013

Part Time Co-founder and CTO

A boutique IT consultancy specialising in phone apps and be-spoke web development projects. I am mainly involved in IT Project Management and Sales.

Lucsan Capital, Sydney

Mar 2010 - Aug 2010

Software Developer (Contract)

Lucsan Capital is a small-medium sized firm dealing with data migration for banks and other financial institutions. While I was working there, I was involved in re-factoring and building new features for their in-house data-migration suite written in C# .Net, and SQL Server. I helped them design a WPF based add-in that would auto-generate workflow diagrams showing migration status and other charts.

Adept Business Systems, Sydney

Mar 2008 - Mar 2010

R & D Developer

I was involved in a large scale project migrating a CRM software for Commercial Real-Estate firms, from a legacy desktop Progress Software based platform to a Web Application (now called SurgaCentral). I was also involved in supporting their legacy applications from time to time.

Satyam Computer Services, Sydney

Sep 2006 - Feb 2008

Sales Assistant

At Satyam I was assisting the Regional Sales head helping him with number-crunching, sales trends for his team, tracking lost purchase orders and invoices, as well as assist setting up monthly sales meetings. In the first year, I helped them track down and retrieve millions of dollars of lost revenue from their biggest clients in Australia. I was sitting in meetings with managers and senior execs from big companies, which gave me a strong basis to learn and grow in my career.

Education

Demandware Jan 2015

 $Front-end\ development\ in\ Demandware\ , E-Commerce/Electronic\ Commerce$

Agile Australia 2013

Agile Project Management - http://courses.scrum.org/about/lachlan-heasman

Sitecore 2012

Sitecore Certified Professional, Sitecore CMS

University of Technology, Sydney

2003 - 2007

Bachelors of Engineering, Software, Software Engineering